Guide to the Consumer Reports. George Brunn papers, 1955-1966 RL.11860
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports. George Brunn papers
1955-1966
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports (Firm)
RL.11860
2.0 Linear Feet
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. George Brunn was a lawyer, municipal judge and consumer advocate primarily in California, and a member of Consumers Union's Board of Directors and Executive Committee in the 1960s and 1970s. The George Brunn papers include primarily correspondence and other materials relating to the establishment of the Association of California Consumers, along with some materials pertaining to other cooperative associations, consumer advocacy groups and the New York Office of Consumer Counsel. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: California Files; New York Office of Consumer Counsel; Publications
Biographical / Historical
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. George Brunn was a lawyer, municipal judge and consumer advocate primarily in California, and a member of Consumers Union's Board of Directors and Executive Committee in the 1960s and 1970s. He was born in Vienna, Austria in 1924 and emigrated to the U.S. Brunn attended Stanford University (AB 1947, JD 1950) and entered a law practice in California. Beginning in 1958 Brunn served on the California Consumer Council; he was a co-founder of the Association of California Consumers around this time and served on the Executive Board from 1959-1966. In 1966 Brunn was appointed to the Municipal Court of Berkeley. He joined the Board of Directors of Consumers Union in 1966, serving a number of terms, and joined the Executive Committee in 1973. Brunn was active in the launch of Consumers Union's West Coast Office in 1975. After retirement Brunn lived in the San Francisco area, where he died in 2014.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Consumer Reports. George Brunn papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2019[year].
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Consumer Reports Archives records
Consumer Reports. Advocacy records
Consumer Reports. Colston E. Warne papers
Consumer Reports. Persia Campbell papers
Collection Overview
The George Brunn papers include primarily correspondence and other materials relating to the establishment of the Association of California Consumers, along with some materials pertaining to other cooperative associations, consumer advocacy groups and the New York Office of Consumer Counsel.
Consumer advocacy; consumer protection; Brunn, George; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Campbell, Persia Crawford, 1898-1974
- California Files, 1957-1966; 1
  - Association of California Consumers, 1958-1966; 1
    - Automobile conditional sales (AB2252), 1961 (Box 1)
    - Automobile conditional sales (AB2252), 1961 (Box 4)
    - Automobile repairs, 1961-1963 (Box 1)
    - Automobile repairs, 1961-1963 (Box 4)
    - Bylaws, correspondence, 1965 (Box 1)
    - California Consumer newsletter, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Estes Kefauver, 1959-1961 (Box 1)
    - Household goods carriers regulation, 1961-1966 (Box 4)
    - Legislative development, 1958-1959 (Box 1)
    - Mildred Edie Brady speech, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Reports, correspondence, etc., 1960-1966 (Box 1)
    - Retail food packaging, 1964 (Box 4)
    - Unemployment conference, 1958; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - California Consumers Association, 1958-1959; 2
    - Correspondence, draft constitution, etc., 1958-1959 (Box 1)
  - Office of Consumer Counsel (Helen Ewing Nelson), 1957-1964; 3
    - 1965 legislation advance planning, 1964 (Box 1)
    - 1965 legislation advance planning, 1964 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, reports, etc., 1961-1962; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Correspondence--Legislation, 1962 (Box 1)
    - Development of Consumer Counsel plan, 1957-1959 (Box 4)
    - Gov. Edmund Brown address, 1960 (Box 4)
    - Legislation, 1961 (Box 4)
    - Packaging and labeling, 1962-1964; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Program Advisory Committee, 1960-1961; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Program Advisory Committee, 1960-1961 (Box 4)
    - Projects, 1959-1960 (Box 2)
    - Releases, speeches, etc., 1960-1961; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Releases, speeches, etc., 1960-1961; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Weights and measures, 1959-1960; 1964; 2 folders (Box 2)
- New York Office of Consumer Counsel (Persia Campbell), 1955-1958; 2
  - Bulletins, 1958 (Box 2)
  - Consumer Laws in Action, 1957-1958 (Box 3)
  - How Much Legal Protection Does New York State Give the Consumer?, 1956-1958 (Box 3)
  - Milk Consumption Habits in the Greater New York Market, September-October 1955, 1957 (Box 3)
  - Pamphlets, 1958 (Box 3)
  - Persia Campbell--Baffled by Bait Bargains (radio script), 1957 (Box 3)
  - Phony Bargain Claims and Practices, 1957 (Box 3)
  - Releases, etc., 1955-1958 (Box 4)
- Publications, 1957-1958; 3
  - AFL-CIO--Consumer Beware!: A Guide to Installment Buying, 1957 (Box 3)
  - AFL-CIO--Labor's Economic Review, 1957-1958 (Box 3)
  - California Farm Research and Legislative Committee--California Farm Reporter newsletter, 1958 (Box 3)
  - California labor councils--Save Our State from the Compulsory Open Shop, 1958 (Box 3)
  - Cooperative associations pamplets and newsletters, 1957-1958 (Box 3)
  - Rutgers University conference papers--Quality Control and the Consumer Conference, 1957 (Box 3)